Zhengwei Bai

POSTGRADUATE STUDENT · JUNIOR SPECIALIST · MACHINE LEARNING · AUTONOMOUS DRIVING
Beijing Jiaotong University Technology Mansion, Haidian District, Beijing, China

Summary.

My research interests are machine learning based control and decision-making methods for Connected and Automated Vehicles (CAVs). My current focus is to explore enhanced autonomous driving strategies for CAVs under signalized intersections by combining Learning-based and Rulebased algorithms, which is also the core of my master thesis topic.

Education _____

Beijing Jiaotong University

Beijing, China

M.S. in Transportation Information Engineering and Control

Sep. 2017 - Jul. 2020

• GPA: 86.6/100.0. (TOP 5%). Awarded the graduate students first-class scholarship for two consecutive years.

Beijing Jiaotong University

Beijing, China

B.E. in Electronic Information and Engineering

Sep. 2013 - Jun. 2017

• GPA: 89.3/100.0. (TOP 3%). Awarded the outstanding graduates in Beijing Jiaotong University.

Experience ___

Machine Learning Based Eco-driving Approach -- University of California, Riverside. [C3], [J2]

California, U.S.

Visiting Scholar - Junior Specialist with Dr.Peng Hao, Dr.Guoyuan Wu and Prof.Matthew Barth.

June. 2019 - Sep. 2019

- Design and Develop a reinforcement learning simulator by using Unity3D (C#) and Tensorflow (Python): a signalized intersection with mixed traffic and propose a time-efficient Eco-Driving Approach for CAVs.
- The experiments shown that the proposed Hybrid Reinforcement learning (HRL) method can save 1.2%-2.9% travel time and reduce 12.25%-47.5% energy consumption comparing with several baselines.

Swarm-intelligent Vehicle Control Theory and Test Verification under i-VICS. [J1]

Beijing, China

Project Researcher with Prof.Wei Shangguan & Prof.Baigen Cai

Sep. 2018 - PRESENT

- · Trying to propose a cooperative driving strategy to achieve better time-efficient driving performance for multi-vehicles.
- The purpose is to reduce 10-20% travel time in mixed urban traffic.

Machine Learning Based CAVs Control and Driving Strategy under Heterogeneous Traffic. [C1], [C2]

Beijing, China

Project Researcher with Prof.Wei Shangguan & Prof.Baigen Cai

Oct. 2017 - Sep.2019

- Proposed a deep neural network called spatiotemporal LSTM to generate the steering angle output by fitting in the raw image data.
- · Proposed a deep Reinforcement Learning (deep RL) based high-level driving control algorithm to achieve ego-efficient driving.
- The experiments shown that the proposed method can improve 25.2-36.3% driving speed on dense highway.

Intelligent Transportation Information Management System (ITIMS) -- Siemens Ltd.

Zhuhai, China

Software Engineer with Dr.Dakai Yang

Jun. 2018 - Oct. 2018

- Developed Five Web Service Modules (Java) of the ITIMS including bus, taxi, intersection, traffic signal, and flow detection.
- Developed several high-reliable multi-source API (C) which connect to the Traffic Police Department in Zhuhai.
- Management and maintenance overall service infrastructure utilizing remote controller, Oracle & Mysql database.

Sangtian Island Autopilot Test Site Construction Proposal (Winning bid) -- Siemens Ltd.

Suzhou, China

Proposal Author with Dr.Dakai Yang

Jul. 2018 - Aug. 2018

- Analyze the equipment layout requirements (such as video perception, V2X communication, geomagnetic sensors, etc.) of the test site.
- Designed the automatic driving test scenarios basing on the site characteristics (such as the car-flowing scenario, overtaking scenario, obstacles recognition, etc).
- Wrote the most part (over 80%) of the proposal (20134 words in total) and made an oral presentation to the local transportation department.

High-speed Railway Based BeiDou Fusion Positioning Performance Test

Shenyang, China

Software Engineer with Dr.Debiao Lu

May. 2018 - Jun. 2018

- · Test the performance of the GPS/BeiDou/IMU fusion positioning under high-speed motion scenario using SPAN, UB380 recorder.
- Continuous testing on the Beijing-Zhangjiakou Railway (On the CR400 Train) for 7 days, 10 hours a day.

Field Strength Test System (FST) -- China Railway Urumqi Railway Administration Group Co.,Ltd. [T1]

Urumqi, China Sep. 2016 - Jun. 2017

Software Engineer with Prof.Wei Shangguan

- Design and developed a MFC framework based windows software (about 15,000 lines of C++ code) for the novel wireless FST system.
- Developed and tested the hardware system (collecting and packaging the sensor data such as ODO, GPS and TAX) of the FST system.
- · Testing the communication-field strength along the railway between Urumqi railway station and Akesu railway station (2018km in total).

OCTOBER 24, 2019 ZHENGWEI-BAI · CURRICULUM VITAE

	& Ongoing Papers	
	Peng Hao, Matthew Barth, "Hybrid Reinforcement Learning for Multi-Sensor Based ng at Signalized Intersections"	TRB2020
Accepted		Aug. 2019
High-level Driving B	Baigen Cai, Wei Shangguan* and Linguo Chai, "Deep Reinforcement Learning Based ehavior Decision-making Model in Heterogeneous Traffic", arXiv:1902.05772v2 ar, 300+ Reads on ReaserchGate, Oral Presentation	CCC2019 Jan. 2019
		000. 2070
· · · · · · · · · · · · · · · · · · ·	eng Hao, Wei Shangguan*, Baigen Cai, Matthew Barth, "Eco-Driving Strategy for mated Vehicles at Signalized Intersections: a Hybrid Reinforcement Learning Framewor	Ongoing Present
[J1] Zhengwei Bai, V	Vei Shangguan*, Bgaigen Cai, "Cooperative Driving Strategy for Connected and in Dense Traffic: A Deep Reinforcement Learning Approach."	Ongoing
Trutonomous venicies		
Preparing for IEEE T-IV		Present
Preparing for IEEE T-IV [T1] Zhengwei Bai, E	Baigen Cai*, "Design and Implementation of Novel Wireless Field Strength Test System."	Thesis
Preparing for IEEE T-IV [T1] Zhengwei Bai, F Outstanding Undergradua		Thesis
Preparing for IEEE T-IV [T1] Zhengwei Bai, E Outstanding Undergradua Presentation [Oral] The 2018 Chin	ate Graduation Project Thesis	Thesis May. 2017 Xi'an, China Dec. 2018
Preparing for IEEE T-IV [T1] Zhengwei Bai, E Outstanding Undergradua Presentation [Oral] The 2018 Chin Introduced our working o [Oral] Suzhou Trans	nte Graduation Project Thesis nese Automatic Congress Session: Unmanned Control System	Thesis May. 2017 Xi'an, China
Preparing for IEEE T-IV [T1] Zhengwei Bai, F Outstanding Undergradua Presentation [Oral] The 2018 Chin Introduced our working o [Oral] Suzhou Trans Introduced the integrated	nese Automatic Congress Session: Unmanned Control System In deep learning based motion planning for autonomous vehicle. portation Department: The Integrated Solution for Autopilot Test Site	Thesis May. 2017 Xi'an, China Dec. 2018 Suzhou, China
Preparing for IEEE T-IV [T1] Zhengwei Bai, F Outstanding Undergradua Presentation [Oral] The 2018 Chin Introduced our working o [Oral] Suzhou Trans Introduced the integrated Skills	nese Automatic Congress Session: Unmanned Control System In deep learning based motion planning for autonomous vehicle. portation Department: The Integrated Solution for Autopilot Test Site solution for Sangtian Island Autopilot Test Site Construction Proposal.	Thesis May. 2017 Xi'an, Chino Dec. 2018 Suzhou, Chino
Preparing for IEEE T-IV [T1] Zhengwei Bai, F Outstanding Undergradua Presentation [Oral] The 2018 Chin Introduced our working o [Oral] Suzhou Trans Introduced the integrated Skills	nese Automatic Congress Session: Unmanned Control System In deep learning based motion planning for autonomous vehicle. portation Department: The Integrated Solution for Autopilot Test Site solution for Sangtian Island Autopilot Test Site Construction Proposal. Python: Application of Machine Learning Algorithms C/C++: Application of the embedded systems & MFC software development C#: Application of the Unity-ML Based Simulation Environment Development Java: Application of a spring framework based Java EE project (Siemens: ITIMS)	Thesis May. 2017 Xi'an, Chino Dec. 2018 Suzhou, Chino
Preparing for IEEE T-IV [T1] Zhengwei Bai, E Outstanding Undergradua Presentation [Oral] The 2018 Chin Introduced our working o [Oral] Suzhou Trans Introduced the integrated Skills Programming	nese Automatic Congress Session: Unmanned Control System In deep learning based motion planning for autonomous vehicle. Portation Department: The Integrated Solution for Autopilot Test Site Integrated Solution For Sangtian Island Autopilot Test Site Construction Proposal. Python: Application of Machine Learning Algorithms Integrated Solution For Software development Integrated Solution For Software Gevelopment Integrated Software Gevelopment Integrated Software Gevelopment Integrated Software Gevelopment Integra	Thesis May. 2011 Xi'an, China Dec. 2018 Suzhou, China

Honors & Awards

2018	Graduate students first-class scholarship, Beijing Jiaotong University	Beijing, China
2018	2nd Prize, (top 10%), "BJTU Huiguang Cup" Graduate Academic Culture Festival Essay Competition	Beijing, China
2016	1st Prize, (top 1%), "Nokia Cup" Innovation Competition Final	Beijing, China
2016	2nd Prize, Beijing Electronic Design Competition Final	Beijing, China
2015	China National Scholarship, (top 1%), Ministry of Education of the People's Republic of China	Beijing, China
2015	Excellent Student Cadre Sholarship, (top 3%), Beijing Jiaotong University	Beijing, China

Misc_

Conference reviewer, TRB2020, CCC 2019, CAC 2018 **Deputy Director**, the College Youth League Committee, BJTU **Student Secretary**, the School League general branch, BJTU

Fall 2018 - PRESENT Fall 2014 - Spring 2015 Fall 2015 - Spring 2016